JULIAN CAMERON

JUNIOR FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

o76 429 1257
juliancameron79@gmail.com
juliancameron.se
github.com/juliancameron79
linkedin.com/in/julian-cameron

Tegvägen 26, 175 53 Järfälla

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

I am a Full Stack Developer with a passion for frontend development. I have always had an interest in working with technology and design; from working in a reprographics shop on the high street, consulting designing and producing business cards stationery flyers posters and more in-house to having a successful career in the financial sector for over 10 years. Now I am at the beginning of what will be another successful career within software development.

EDUCATION

Code Institute — Dublin, Ireland

Diploma in Full Stack Software Development - EQF Level 5 November 2019 – January 2021

The course is credit-rated by Edinburgh Napier University as a Diploma in Software Development. It is a level 8 on the Scottish Credit and Qualifications Framework which is equivalent to Level 5 on the European Qualifications Framework.

The course is designed to build up skills and knowledge in an incremental manner. New-found skills are tested by completing code challenges and following walkthrough mini-projects before creating and building four milestone projects and at the end graduate with a diploma in Software Development.

The course content starts with HTML Fundamentals CSS Fundamentals and User-Centric Frontend Development, the covered modules are concluded with the first milestone project. The next set of modules covered are Javascript Fundamentals Interactive Frontend Development and concludes with the second milestone project. The third set of modules are Python Fundamentals Practical Python Data-Centric Development and concludes with the third milestone project. The final module is Full Stack Frameworks with Django and the fourth and final milestone project.

Middlesex University - London, England

Higher National Diploma in Multimedia/Graphic Design

SKILLS

Technical Skills

- HTML CSS Javascript Python Django Flask Figma
- Boostrap
 MySQL
 MongoDB
 Heroku
 AWS

Transferable Skills

- Teamwork Time Management Problem Solving Communication Creative
- Confident
 Creative
 Leadership
 Project Management

EXPERIENCE

Production Assistant, Datasite, Merrill Corporation; London — 2005-2017

I started as a Production Assistant, prepping documents, scanning documents, quality checking documents, uploading documents to the Dataroom, carrying out document site checks, setting security for both users and document and folder level. I later became Weekend Production Lead where my

duties involved supervising all department processes, producing department reports, sending detailed shift handovers, managing staff levels and liaising with project managers clients and vendors. After a company-wide reorganisation, the department was rolled into the project management department where I became Assistant Project Manager.

- Replied to users enquiries on product and tool features via phone, email and live chat.
- Assisted users with setup and configuration of tools and features within Datasite's technology products.
- Supported users experiencing simple or more complex issues with product or tools.
- Troubleshoot and answer user questions.
- Provided educational support on the platform's capabilities and functionality to users and colleagues.
- Built positive relationships while being proactive and anticipating users needs.
- Participated in mentoring and guidance of less experienced colleagues.

Graphic Designer, Connections Communication; London - 2002-2004

- Designed promotional material for multiple EU and local authority funded media courses.
- Led the in-house rebrand team for Connections Communication and sister company Ravenscourt Media.
- Carried out general office duties as well as assisted IT and equipment hire sections with support for students and staff. Assisted with a number of events to showcase student's work.

HOBBIES

I am an avid home cook and I love exploring different cooking styles and techniques, of late I have discovered the joy of carbon steel pans and stainless steel pans. Other interests of mine are maintaining a private family network drive, I am also an amateur photographer with an interest in nature and street photography, I am in the process of producing a nature portfolio.